&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：Doug Crockford有句名言，
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: Doug Crockford famously said,
iif一个功能有时有用，有时很危险，并且
iif a feature is sometimes useful and sometimes dangerous, and
如果有更好的选择，那么总是使用更好的选择。
if there's a better option, then always use the better option.
事实上，几乎所有好的部分都源于
As a matter of fact almost all of the good parts stems from
这是一个基本的观点。
this one foundational perspective.
我尊重道格为我们的行业所做的
I respect what Doug has done for our industry,
但我非常不同意这一观点。
but I couldn't disagree more with this prospective.
我部分不同意这一点，因为我们把这个原则抛诸脑后，
Partially I disagree with this because we throw this principle around,
我们甚至没有说出这些话的意思。
and we don't even say what we mean by these words.
那么什么是有用的危险，只有狗认为有用的危险？
So what is useful in what is dangerous, only what dog thinks is useful dangerous?
有用的危险有什么普遍的定义吗？
Is there some universal definition for useful dangerous?
有没有更好的选择？
How about better option?
我们如何定义更好的选择？
How do we define better option?
有没有什么通用的标准可以让我们更好地衡量？
Is there some universal standard by which we measure better?
这种说法在抽象意义上是没有用处的。
The statement is not useful in its abstract sense.
它是在抽象意义上使用的，但它没有用处。
It's used in its abstract sense, but it's not useful.
所以，让我把我的标记放在沙子上
So, let me put my mark in the sand and
告诉你我说的话是什么意思，好吗？
tell you what I mean by those words, okay?
第一，有用的是当读者专注于什么是重要的时候，
Number one, useful is when the reader is focused on what's important,
危险的是当读者不能说出将要发生的事情时。
and dangerous is when the reader can't tell what's gonna happen.
更好的是当读者理解代码时。
And better is when the reader understands the code.
&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：所以你可以把这个原则
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: So you could take that principle and
应用它的具体含义，但你不能简单地把这句话当作
apply the specific meaning to it, but you can't simply throw that sentence around as
这是你避免学习整个语言部分的理由。
a justification for why you avoid learning an entire part of the language.
&GT；&GT；Kyle Simpson：在Doug看来，这里的一个大问题是，有一个更好的选择，
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: The big crux here is, in Doug's opinion, there's a better option,
这就是不学习和理解类型。
which is just don't learn and understand types.
我的观点是一点都不好，
My perspective is that's not better at all,
因为它导致开发人员系统地不理解他们的代码。
because it leads to developers systemically not understanding their code.
这并不是因为它导致更少的理解。
It's not better because it leads to less understanding.
我想让你明白的是，明知故犯是不负责任的
The takeaway, I want you to get here is that it is irresponsible to knowingly
避免使用能够并且确实提高代码可读性的功能。
avoid usage of a feature that can and does improve code readability.
这不仅仅是简单的，你没有利用一些伟大的东西，
It is not just simply, you're not taking advantage of some great things,
你实际上是在让代码变得更糟。
you are actually making code worse off.
不仅是为了你未来的自己，也是为了所有其他需要阅读和
Not only for your future self, but for all other people that need to read and
维护您的代码。
maintain your code.
&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：这个工具存在，不学习和使用它是不负责任的。
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: That tool exists and it's irresponsible not to learn and use it.